Daniel Victory

(281) 961-1201 | danieljvictory@gmail.com

Software Engineer | Full Stack Web Dev | Chemical Engineer

Bringing a lifetime of performance, five years of chemical process engineering, and a people-oriented approach to software. Looking to start in a junior role in full stack, back end, front end, data, or DevOps

Skillset

Languages, Frameworks, & Libraries: HTML, CSS, Javascript, React, node.js, express, MongoDB, mongoose, Python, Django, SQL, Postgresql, bit.io, VBA, AWS, Azure, RESTful APIs, SPA, MVC

Programs: VS Code, ChatGPT, Microsoft Office Suite, Microsoft Sharepoint, Google Workspace

Soft Skills: Agile Methodology, Project Alignment, Mentoring, Public Speaking, Written and Verbal Communication, Stagecraft (Performance, Acting, Improvisation, Directing)

Awareness: Data Analysis/Science (numpy, pandas, seaborn), DevOps & Networking (CI/CD, Docker, Kubernetes)

Recent Projects

circleUp Social Media platform, including authorization and commenting (python, Postgresql, Django, Heroku)

OpenEncounter A TTRPG encounter designer built, featuring user signup and login (javascript, node.js, MongoDB, Heroku) World Calendar API interface, using Calendarific, allowing users to look up all official world holidays (javascript, node.js)

Employment History

Chevron Corporation, Technology Marketing (TEMA)

2017 - 2022

Technical Service Engineer:

- 2021 2022
- Provide expert technical support for the residuum hydrotreating units in major refineries in southeast Asia.
 - This includes catalyst loading, unit start-up, and general monitoring and troubleshooting.
- Provide valuable unit insights to client to model advanced fluid flow and catalyst chemical degradation

Process Design Engineer: 2017 - 2021

- Delivered 11 projects and 8 studies to clients by working as part of multiple cross-functional teams
 - Process Role: system simulation, stream data generation, equipment design
 - Systems Role: P&ID development from standards, pipe sizing, pump specification, flare system estimation
- Assisted in update and verification of 300+ project-critical procedures as representative of process engineers

Group Manager for Siemens COMOS database:

2018-2021

2018 - 2021

- Took over management of project and revenue-critical engineering tool without formal training.
- Facilitated better project design through data querying, object creation, error correction, and peer education
- Led a 6 month training and work initiative to improve accuracy and functionality of the database
 - Completed 50% of 80+ item, 3 year backlog while providing training to peers
 - Enabled the close of each item by providing action plans and personalized coworking sessions with peers
 - Hosted weekly Agile-style office hours and monthly department wide update briefings

Filtration Technology Point of Contact:

2018-2021

2017 - 2021

- Managed filtration vendor relationships to align department with current available technology
- Facilitated new product testing by aligning internal researchers with external vendors.

TEMA Intern, Process Design and Engineering

Summer 2016

- Reduce processing time for column design from full day to single hour by creating a new excel based VBA tool
- Enabled easy transfer of client data for internal technical service team by creation of standardized monitoring template

Training: Chevron Data Science Development Program (DSDP), Chevron Agile Academy, Chevron Technical University (CTU)

Provenance Consulting - Process Safety Management Co-op Intern

2015 - 2016

Improved overall process facility safety through creation, updating, and organization of Process Safety Information (PSI) documentation including authoring of proof-test procedures to audit independent protection layers

Other - Children's Theatre Summer Camp Counselor, Legal Assistant, Restaurant/Bar Server, Eagle Scout

Pre-2015

Education

General Assembly, Software Engineering Remote Immersive	2023
Amazon Web Services (AWS), Certificate: Certified Cloud Practitioner	2021
DataCamp, Certificate: Python Programmer	2020
Chevron, Certificate: Data Science Development Program	2020
The University of Texas at Austin, Bachelor of Science in Chemical Engineering, GPA: 3.6	2013-2016
The University of Evansville, Bachelor of Arts in Theatre Performance, GPA: 3.9	2010-2012 (Transfer)